A health insurance
policy that pays the entire hospital bill, no matter how big the hospital bill is during a hospital admission. A health insurance policy that allows us to use
our submitted word once for a year and
refill it as many times as we want in the same year. A health insurance policy that
allows us to use the same submitted word no matter how many times we claim.
A health insurance
policy that adds 100% to the submitted word every year.  A health insurance policy that allows us to
put in as many crores of rupees as we want, as a sum
assured
.
That is ICC Lombard's Elevate.
Before talking about this product, you should
know what the ICC Group is.  A company with a tradition of 70 years in
banking,
investment and insurance
experience [Music] A
company with more than 20 years in general insurance A company
with a claim settlement ratio of more than 98 percent A
company with a customer base of more than 30 million [Music] That is ICC
Lampard's Elevate Now I am going to talk
about the benefits that are inbuilt in this policy. The
first of them is the limit on room rent.
At the time of admission, we can use a single AC private room
[Music]
ICU expenses CCU expenses
Doctor's consultation fee
Pharmacy expenses All these are
covered in this. Next is
pre-hospitalization expenses i.e.
tests related to the same disease for 90 days before hospital admission Doctor consultation Pharmacy
All these are covered  Another thing that is being done is
post-hospitalization, which covers the tests for the next 180 days after
admission and discharge due to an illness,
doctor consultation [music],
pharmacy, all of this
.  Another is day care
treatment.  Minor surgeries that do not require hospitalization for more than 24 hours,
such as cataract surgery,
can be performed.  Now, chemotherapy and dialysis are all
covered under this.
Another is the AYUSH benefit.
After diagnosing any disease [music],
its treatment can be covered by Ayurveda,
Homeopathy, or Siddhi Unani
treatments up to the submisha
.  Now free and
post-hospitalization benefits will
be available here as well.  Another is
organ donor.  If the insured
person is to receive an organ,
all expenses related to it and
all expenses related to the hospitalization of the organ donor will be
covered by UptoSubmitted.
Another is domiciliary treatment, which means
treatments given at home as per the advice of a doctor, such as IV
medications or
treatments like dialysis or chemotherapy.
Another is surrogate mother cover, which means coverage for treatments like a
surrogate uterus.
Next is
oocyte [music] donor cover, which means
coverage for IVF treatments.
Next is a benefit.
Coverage for bariatric surgery is mandatory with a two-year
waiting period, which means that if a
person's excess weight is
considered dangerous to his health,
we get full coverage for this bariatric surgery as per the advice of a doctor.
Another is inpatient
dental treatment, which means dental treatments that
require hospitalization for more than 24 hours, whether due to an
illness
or an accident. Upto
submitted coverage is available. Now, the most
important benefit to mention.
Restoration benefit is the
amount that the company has allowed us to use for a year. That is what is
called a summated benefit. Even if
we use it once, it
is a benefit that we can refill as many times as we want in the same year. However, if
we are discharged due to an illness
but are
readmitted for another illness, this
restoration benefit will also be applicable.
Another is ambulance cover. In
case of any emergency,
it is the coverage of an ambulance to shift the patient from one hospital to another hospital or from the place of accident or from home to the hospital. This is
available up to sub-measured. We can
use this coverage. Next is the
wellness program. If we are ready to
suffer a lot, if we are ready to walk or
run, we will
get a 30 percent discount on our renewal as we earn points. Another benefit is
loyalty bonus. No matter
how many times we claim in a year or not, we will get
20 percent sub-measured for the next year.  You
can get it by adding on, for example, if
we have a sub-fund of Rs 10 lakh now,
next year it will be Rs 12, the
year after that it will be Rs 14, and so on
until we reach 100 percent sub-fund, and then until we
reach Rs 20 lakh, this benefit will
be available to us. Another benefit is modern treatment,
modern methods of
treatment, robotic surgery,
laparoscopy surgery, all these are
covered up to the sub-fund. Now,
do not take any health insurance that does not have modern treatment coverage or has any sub-limits in it, which says that you can use this amount. Now, what I am going to talk about is the
add-on benefits in this. We
only need to add it if we need it. The
first of these
is Infinity Care. No matter
how big a hospital bill we
have once in our lifetime, the company
will pay it all.  Another is the power
booster.  This means that regardless of how many times we have a
claim or not,
100% of the amount of the submission that the company has allowed us to use will continue to be added to the next year
.  So
this will be added for unlimited time.   If you
look at it this way, if you currently have an insurance policy with a submission of Rs 10 lakh, and
this rider is also included in it, then
after the next ten years, it will become
an insurance policy with a submission of Rs 1 crore
.  Another is Jump Start,
which means that if we want to claim for illnesses we have at the time of taking out a policy, we have to wait
three years.  That is,
they have mentioned diseases like diabetes, cholesterol, hypertension, asthma. If you add
this rider, the claim for these diseases will
be available from the 31st day.  Another is
maternity cover.  There is a
two-year waiting
period to receive maternity cover.  The maximum amount is up to one lakh rupees
.  It is mandatory for both husband and wife to
be on the policy for two years.
It is available for a maximum of three pregnancies
.  Another added
benefit is the newborn baby cover.
That is, the expenses for all the treatments for a child for the next 90
days
.  There
is a sub limit on it.  This means that this coverage is only twice as much as the
sub-issue of the maternity coverage
.
This benefit is available only to those who have taken out a rider called maternity cover
Newborn vaccination cover is someone else's benefit.   If you
have a child, it covers
all the mandatory vaccines for the next year of life,
up to a maximum of Rs. 10,000
.  Another add-on benefit is
worldwide cover.  This is a coverage for any illness
diagnosed in India and requiring further
treatment in another country on an
inpatient basis or in a day
care facility
.  This is available for a maximum of 90 days per year, and you
cannot stay in another country for more than 45 days at a time.
This claim can only be made by those up to the age of 65
.  The other is claim
protector or consumables.
Consumables are disposable items that we cannot use again and again after using them once
.  Our mask gloves cotton
is the coverage for this type of item.
Almost 100 percent of consumables are
covered under this, and in a hospital
bill, especially for treatments like surgery,
25 percent of the hospital
bill will be
spent on consumables.  Therefore,
we definitely need to
take out insurance that covers 100% of consumables.  The other is the inflation
protector.  Inflation in India
Medical [Music] Inflation ranges from 10 to 15%
.  This means that treatment costs are increasing by
10 to 15 percent every year
.
If that's the case, they will keep increasing the
amount of the sum assured according to this inflation rate.
Another
add-on benefit is domestic air
ambulance cover.  If in case of any emergency, a
patient needs to be transferred from one place to
another through an air ambulance, then
we get the coverage of Upto Submitted. The
other is Nursing at Home. If
a patient is discharged from the hospital and required for the
next 10
days, that is, as per
the doctor's advice, a
nurse from the same hospital is assigned as a
home nurse. This is paid at a rate of
Rs. 2000 per day for a maximum of 10 days.
Another add-on
benefit is Prolonged Hospital
Cash. If there is a hospital admission of more than 10 days, then a cash
benefit of Rs. 20 is available. Next is
Compassionate Visit. If the
insured person is
admitted to any city in India and
his
hospitalization is for more than five days, then
his immediate
family member i.e. the
person belonging to the immediate family will get an
economy ticket for the flight to go there
or a
first class ticket for the train.  The maximum amount of ticket up and down is
Rs. 20. This coverage is given. Health
checkup. Every year, the
senior citizens included in the policy can
use up to Rs. 5000 for health checkup,
but it will be
only on a cashless basis, that is, only on the profits related to the
network of this company.
This health checkup
can be done. Personal Accidental
Benefit, that is, if the insured adult dies due to an accident, the
entire submitted amount will be given to his nominee. Even if there is partial
disability, the
company will give a certain amount. Is this add-on benefit available?
Critical illness,
that is, up to twenty critical illnesses,
they say, cancer or
stroke [Music] Open heart surgery. At
the time of such treatment, a certain amount, i.e. up to
submitted, is given, and it will be one time
only.  There are
two other add-on benefits provided in life insurance: Voluntary co-
payment and voluntary deductible. Co-
payment means that every time a
hospital bill comes,
we pay a certain amount and the
company pays the remaining percentage.
[Music] We can choose it according to our preference.
For example, if we have set a
20 percent co-payment at the time of a hospital bill of Rs.
8000, the company
will pay Rs. 2000 and we will have to pay Rs. 8000.
Deductible means that
we have to pay a certain amount on the first bill of the year. The
company will pay the rest. The
company itself pays the entire amount on the second bill. These
two add-on benefits are usually provided to
reduce the premium.
Next is the durable medical
equipment, i.e.
our
walker, wheelchair or
BiPAP machine ventilator, which can be used once and again. All these are
covered in this.
They have given about nine lists here.
Another great added benefit is
teleconsultation.  If we need to,
we can have a doctor's consultation over the phone or via video call as many times as we want in a year
.  Another is the Dependent
Accommodation Benefit.  This means that if
an insured person is
admitted to the hospital, his/her
immediate family member will be given a daily benefit of
Rs. 2,000 for the next 10 days
.  That is, if the insured
person who is admitted is an adult, then
a benefit like this is
given to manage his expenses or the expenses of the person accompanying him. This
is a rider to reduce the maternity waiting period. The
maternity waiting period is two
years, we can reduce it to one year.
Now, if
we
are doing an add benefit called room modifier, even if it is a single AC private
room that is inbuilt in this,
we
can select the highest room available at the time of a hospital admission. Now, if we
want a twin room or a shared accommodation,
we can choose that.  This
is an option where we can select the room according to our preference.  Network
Advantage.  That means [music] if
we are going to be treated in day care
or as an inpatient at hospitals that are in the network with this company, we
will get a 10% discount on our premium.  [Music] Now we've
taken an add-on benefit like this.
But if we do
n't go to the network hospital they mention, we will have to pay a 20 percent
co-payment on each of our bills
[music].  This means that
we will pay 20% of each bill and
the company will pay only the remaining 80%.
Now, I'm going to talk about the
four discounts available in this policy
.  The first of these is the
renewal discount.  If you renew your
policy one month before its expiration, you will
get a two and a half percent discount on your premium.
Next up is the wellness discount.  As we
said earlier, if you're
willing to run and walk as much as you can and
you're
earning as many points as they say, you'll get about a
30% discount on [music] premium
.  Another is the CIBIL score
discount.  If you have a good CIBIL score, you
will get a discount of 15% on each review [music].   The
last discount is the
NRI discount, meaning that if you are an NRI,
you will get a 25 percent discount when you first take out this policy and
you will get a 2.5 percent discount on the premium on each annual renewal.
Now let's talk about the basic features of this policy
.  Who
can become a member of this policy? This policy can be taken by anyone
from 90 days after the birth of a child [Music]
to 125 years of age.
One person can take it alone
or on a family floater basis for a
family of five, three
children and two adults
.  Similarly, you
can pay one year, two years, or three years' premium together.  If you choose to pay this way, you
will get a 10% discount on the second year's premium and a 15% discount on the third year's premium.  The sum assured that can be placed in this is the same as
we said before
[Music] We can select a sum assured ranging from five lakh rupees to how many crores.
No medical checkup is required to issue this policy.
And in some cases, a
medical checkup may be
recommended depending on the health condition.  Now, once this is issued, it's
a [music] policy that we can renew and carry for the rest of our lives.  Now if the policyholder wants to
add a new member, i.e. if the wife wants to
add her husband or the husband wants to add his wife or if the husband wants to add a
child,
it is possible.
They can be added on by paying their extra premium.
Now [Music] The last thing to
say is the waiting period in this.
When can you use it after the policy is issued? You
can claim it from the first day of the policy issue for any accident. Now if you
have any illnesses, you can claim from the 31st day
[Music]. If
you have any critical illness, there is a waiting period of 90 days. You can
claim only after 90 days.
Now if
you have any illnesses at the time of taking the policy, you
can claim for the treatments related to it only after three years or we will have to
take a rider. Later
[Music] There are some slow growing diseases,
i.e. fissure fistula piles, for all these, it is
two years.  There is a waiting period
.  Some treatments will
never receive a claim.   It
could be cosmetic surgery or
alcohol-related
treatments, accidents due to high-risk
sports activities, and
their
treatments. There is a list
of treatments
that are never covered
.  In short,
ICC Lombard's Elevate is an affordable health insurance policy with all the essential benefits. There is no such thing as a disadvantage in it. There is no
need to take any maternity benefit. It is
really very cost-effective.
We have many sublimits in it. If you
are looking at it that way, then once you
eliminate one or two minor disadvantages,
ICC Lombard's Elevate is the best health insurance [music] policy.